Batteries are highly regulated.
To ensure they are properly categorized, we need to collect specific
details about the battery.
When selling a battery or a product with a battery, you will be asked
a few additional questions.
You are required to provide accurate information.
Missing or
inaccurate information can lead to safety incidents, delays in setting up the product
and getting it to customers quickly, and regulatory action.
Let's get started.
What
is the composition of the battery you are selling?
Common composition types are Lithium
ion, Lithium metal, alkaline, and nickel metal hydride.
Most of the time, the composition
will be printed on the battery.
Or, it can also be found in the manufacturer's documentation.
If you are selling a Lithium battery, we will ask you a few more questions.
How many
batteries are included in your listing?
The number of batteries is a critical piece of
information for us.
Let's take a look at a listing for a set of walkie-talkie radios.
At first glance, you may think of each radio using one battery.
Really, the complete listing
contains two batteries, so your listing should specify two batteries.
You will also be asked
about the number of cells.
Battery regulations make a distinction between a single cell battery
and a multi-cell battery.
Common examples of single cell batteries would be the double
A batteries used in a flashlight, or the coin cell found in your watch.
A common example
of a multi-cell battery is the battery in your laptop.
Laptop batteries can have up
to nine Lithium ion cells linked together within the plastic battery casing to provide
longer battery life.
The number of cells for multi-cell batteries can typically be found
on the manufacturer's website or in their product documentation.
What is the weight
of the battery or batteries?
This refers to the total weight of all Lithium batteries
minus the product.
Batteries can be weighed manually, but this should also be available
in the manufacturer's documentation.
What is the battery type?
Common battery types
are double A, triple A, C-R-1-2-3-A, C-R-2, and 9 volt.
The battery type is usually printed
on the battery, or it can be found in the manufacturer's documentation.
We will also
ask you how the battery is packaged.
There are three ways batteries are typically shipped.
Batteries only, batteries contained in equipment, and batteries packed with equipment.
If you
are selling stand-alone batteries, select batteries only.
For example, a spare laptop
battery, or an external battery charger like a power bank, or if you are including other
products not used by the battery like a bonus charging cord, even a power bank integrated
into a product like a purse for convenient charging is considered batteries only when
answering this question.
Select batteries contained in equipment if you are selling a
battery that is pre-installed in the product or not removable.
For example, tablets, solar
lights, wireless speakers, LED candles, and wireless headphones.
Though you can't see
the battery, these products do contain batteries and are categorized as batteries contained
in equipment.
Select batteries packed with equipment if your listing includes a battery
shipped with the product and it is not pre-installed.
Everyday items that commonly come
with a battery packed alongside it are power tools, flashlights, and digital cameras.
Next,
you will be asked to provide the watt hour rating.
Battery sales are regulated and restricted
based on the watt hour rating.
The maximum allowable watt hour rating can vary by country,
so check Seller Central to ensure that your battery complies with the battery selling
policy for your marketplace.
You can find the watt hours printed on the battery or on
the battery pack.
If the watt hours are not printed on the battery and the manufacturer's
documentation is not available, you can calculate watt hours yourself using this formula.
Milliamp hours divided by 1000 times the voltage.
Check Seller Central Help for more information.
Lithium metal battery sales are also regulated and restricted based on the grams of lithium
contained in the battery.
For this information, check the manufacturer's documentation.
If
the lithium content is not available in the documentation, then it can be calculated using
this formula.
Milliamp hours divided by 1000 times 0.3 to give you the lithium content in
grams.
Need more help answering these questions?
Go to help in Seller Central and videos on
Seller University.
Both are great resources for learning more.
Thank you for helping to
keep our communities and our customers safe.